<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Just 5-Mins</title>
    <link href="https://justfivemins.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://justfivemins.github.io/blog" />
    <updated>2022-08-28T21:03:03+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Tryambak Dasgupta</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://justfivemins.github.io/blog</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Youtube Alert : Horrors of Streetism | Child Beggars</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tryambak Dasgupta</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://justfivemins.github.io/blog/youtube-alert-horrors-of-streetism-or-child-beggars/"/>
        <id>https://justfivemins.github.io/blog/youtube-alert-horrors-of-streetism-or-child-beggars/</id>

        <updated>2022-08-28T21:03:03+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://justfivemins.github.io/blog/media/posts/5/Ep-01.png" alt="" />
                    We've just posted a new video on Youtube about Horrors of Streetism | Child Beggars. Please do check it out on Youtube. Horrors of Streetism - Child Beggars: The children of today are assets of tomorrow. Yet education, which is a fundamental right to every&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://justfivemins.github.io/blog/media/posts/5/Ep-01.png" alt="" />
                <h4>We've just posted a new video on Youtube about Horrors of Streetism | Child Beggars. Please do check it out on <a href="https://youtu.be/pNkQ2xobKzk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><a href="https://youtu.be/pNkQ2xobKzk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Youtube.</a></h4>
<p> </p>
<h1><strong>What's it about?</strong></h1>
<p><strong>Horrors of Streetism - Child Beggars:</strong> The children of today are assets of tomorrow. Yet education, which is a fundamental right to every child in our country, is still a dream for many children in India, especially the ones who are poor, downtrodden and in dire need. Poverty and lack of education are the major factors that lead to desperate acts like child begging, which is one of the most heartbreaking and pertinent problems prevalent in our country. This act of child begging has terribly plagued the lives of thousands of children who have lost their beautiful and innocent childhood by becoming slaves.</p>
<p>Follow Us : <br>Insta : <a href="https://www.instagram.com/just5mins2224/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@just5mins2224</a><br>Twitter : <a href="https://twitter.com/just5mins_in" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@just5mins_in</a><br>Youtube : <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCJVvdllmcZ5B47SoSZPYNYA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Just 5 Mins</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Why housewives not homemakers?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tryambak Dasgupta</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://justfivemins.github.io/blog/why-housewives-not-homemakers/"/>
        <id>https://justfivemins.github.io/blog/why-housewives-not-homemakers/</id>
            <category term="housewives"/>
            <category term="homemaker"/>
            <category term="gender"/>
            <category term="awareness"/>

        <updated>2022-08-19T19:27:08+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://justfivemins.github.io/blog/media/posts/4/spacejoy-9M66C_w_ToM-unsplash-3.jpg" alt="" />
                    Gender roles have changed dramatically over the last few decades. Housewives, this word makes people visualise women dealing with household work. Society has always considered them to be jobless. But should we keep believing in this myth? Only a housewife is expected to nurture and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://justfivemins.github.io/blog/media/posts/4/spacejoy-9M66C_w_ToM-unsplash-3.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Gender roles have changed dramatically over the last few decades. Housewives, this word makes people visualise women dealing with household work. Society has always considered them to be jobless. But should we keep believing in this myth? Only a housewife is expected to nurture and cultivate her family. But is this thinking correct any more? Isn't it the responsibility of even the male members of the family to nurture and cultivate their family? Let's break this stereotype.</p>
<p>However, being a homemaker is not only responsibility of a woman. Before the 20th century, housewives were considered jobless by most of the people in their society. Do you think it is justified? A homemaker is not just a person who carries out household responsibilities but also work towards making their house, a home. In this era woman are not just housewives they are homemakers because they contribute a lot to the family and their work is not just constricted to doing household chores.</p>
<p>The term housewives itself questions gender inequality. So, this gender inequality that has been going on for a century needs to be stopped. We should be careful to not discriminate against the female gender. The females are not born for doing household chores like cooking, cleaning, and all other household activities. They are not born just to manage our lives; they can have their own lives and also fulfil all their dreams.</p>
<p>We have seen this in many cases in which females are emotionally and sometimes physically forced to do all the household activities. This is one of the biggest critical issues in our country. Our country always expects a woman to have a successful job life just to manage their house after marriage or to take care of their children. This is a problem that we should all be aware of. We should create a society where women are not forced to leave their jobs or sacrifice their dreams just because they are married or because they are housewives. Women are not made for just household work; they also have their own dreams or goals that they want to achieve.</p>
<p>Our mothers are housewives as well as homemakers. We get back to our home every day to get that warmth and satisfaction after a hectic day. Also, it is very subjective. Let us ask you a question. What do you consider your mother to be—a housewife or a homemaker?</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Hello World</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tryambak Dasgupta</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://justfivemins.github.io/blog/hello-world/"/>
        <id>https://justfivemins.github.io/blog/hello-world/</id>

        <updated>2022-08-19T04:41:31+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://justfivemins.github.io/blog/media/posts/1/1_OohqW5DGh9CQS4hLY5FXzA.png" alt="Hi" />
                    Hi :) We, the students of Section - A MBA batch of the Institute of Engineering &amp; Management, Kolkata (2022-2024), are starting our own blog to spread different kinds of awareness among the community. Our Socials: We hope you will enjoy your stay. Stay tuned&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://justfivemins.github.io/blog/media/posts/1/1_OohqW5DGh9CQS4hLY5FXzA.png" alt="Hi" />
                <p><em><strong>Hi :)<br><br></strong></em></p>
<p>We, the students of Section - A MBA batch of the <strong>Institute of Engineering &amp; Management, Kolkata</strong> (2022-2024), are starting our own blog to spread different kinds of awareness among the community.</p>
<p><em><strong>Our Socials:</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Youtube - <a href="https://bit.ly/just5minsyt">https://bit.ly/just5minsyt</a></em></li>
<li><em>Instagram - <a href="https://instagram.com/just5mins2224">@just5mins2224</a></em></li>
<li><em>Twitter - <a href="https://twitter.com/just5mins_in">@just5mins_in</a></em></li>
<li><em>Podcast - <strong>Coming Soon</strong></em></li>
</ul>
<p><br>We hope you will enjoy your stay. Stay tuned for more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
